SANJAY SONI

Noida, UP

ssanjay1994@gmail.com

8240340269

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/sanjay-soni-3a4845113

GitHub: https://github.com/ssanjay78/

Website: https://travelguide.pythonanywhere.com

PROFILE

Sr. Software Engineer at **Fourthpointer** (Noida) from Sept 2020 till present date, working on client side **Innovaccer** as a **Consultant**. 3.5 years of total experience in software development with Python.

Developed my own dummy website on travelling and data migration from postgres to elastic and vice versa as mentioned above, source code is in GitHub. Implementing many more features through APIs in it.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES : Python, Java

PYTHON PACKAGES : Django, Djangorestframework, Psycopg2, Elasticsearch, Boto3 (S3),

Pymongo, Paramiko

WEB FRAMEWORK : Django

DATABASE : Mongo DB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Elasticsearch

WEB TECHNOLOGY : HTML, CSS, JS

TOOLS : Postman, Jenkins, Jira, VS Code, PyCharm

AD LOGINS : Azure, Okta, Google, Autho

CLOUD : AWS, PythonAnywhere, Heroku

OPERATING SYSTEM : Windows, Linux (RedHat, Ubuntu)

OTHERS : RESTAPIS, XML, JSON

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Django Developer- UserManagement at Innovaccer; (Sept 2020 - Present)

- Worked on managing all the users creation, their permissions, authorizations on the platform
- Configured SSO login on platform with Azure, Okta, Google and Autho
- Worked on feature enhancements, bug fixes and contributed on planning for the approach
- 95% success rate on closing task parallel to sprint

Technology used in project

Web Framework Django

Python Package djangorestframework, pymongo etc

Tool Postman, VS Code, Robo3T

Database MongoDB

Python Developer- Data Movement in Innovaccer; (Sept 2020 - Present)

• Worked on creating a platform for moving all the records from Postgres to AWS Elastic.

• Done multiple modification in framework to enhance the feature e.g.: Ingestion rate, Error logs etc

• Always up for support on any query, error and movement stuck on prod hours (6pm - 5am IST) also

Technology used in project

Operating System Ubuntu Linux

Python Package Boto3(S3), python-dotenv, requests

Tool AWS Console, VS Code

Database Postgres, Elasticsearch

Python Automation Engineer- IC3 Automation in Cappemini; (Aug 2018-Aug 2020)

• Contributed in building Python framework from scratch to communicate with Linux based app (IC3) through Paramikopackage.

- Created functions to get the input data from excel sheet in a dictionary format iterated through each test cases by Openpyxl package.
- Added a functionality to Browse directory, Start Execution, Cancel the Execution in the middle etc.
- Played a lead role in analyzing Batch Execution failures, fixing them was my prior task, at the end of the project we were able to achieve more than 96% of success rate on every batch execution.
- Developed many Scripts based on the requirements.
- Since I have gained enough knowledge in project, I was assigned to arrange knowledge sharing sessions on IC3, IC3 Automation framework, how to write the script, system setup to all new joiners.
- I have reviewed & tested many of the functions, scripts developed by the team.

Technology used in project

Operating System Red Hat Linux

Python Package Paramiko, NumPy, Openpyxl, Pillow

Tools PyCharm, VMware, WinSCP, QAC

Database MySQL

Environment Python, XML, JSON, SQL

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Appreciated as STAR employee in Capgemini
- Three times **Outstanding Contribution in Delivery** in Capgemini
- Appreciation mails from VP in Innovaccer

CERTIFICATIONS

- Completed certifications in **Python Programming & Linux shell scripting**
- Certified in **Python** from **Coursera**
- Automation Engineer Practitioner Certified

QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication

University Institute of Technology, Burdwan University; West Bengal;

High School and Intermediate

Vikram Main School, Howrah; West Bengal;

Academic Highlights and Achievements:

GATE Qualified 2017 - 90.66 Percentile

BE Percentage- 70% Marks

Class XII – 72% Marks

Class X - 74% Marks

PERSONAL DETAILS

Birth Date : 20-Jan-1994

Residence : Howrah, West Bengal

Marital Status : Unmarried Gender : Male

Permanent Address : Rajkumar Apartment, A-102, Jay Bibi Road Ghusuri,

Howrah-711107, West Bengal